This morning, Aaliyah prepares for an upcoming video conference meeting.
In this meeting, she will be sharing a change story with the department heads from across the entire organization.
“David, hi. Do you have a couple of minutes?” “Of course.”
“Let me guess. Is this about the video presentation?”
“You know me too well, David. I have to admit I’m really worried about doing this on video.
You know, I love presentations, but this video meeting — what if people simply tune out?
You did an amazing job at the board meeting last week. Can you share some tips with me?”
“Sure, I’m happy to.
With something like a change story, it’s really important to think about your presence, especially if it’s virtual.
You have a great voice, so you’re off to a good start.
Is this usually where you take your video conference calls?” “Umm, yes it is.”
“Okay, we have to find a better spot for you. You’ll need a well-lit room with a non-distracting background.”
“You’re right, I get so distracted looking at other people’s backgrounds. But then I didn’t think about my own.”
“Practice makes perfect, my friend.”
“Virtual is such a pain. What else should I keep in mind?”
“Honestly, one of the toughest things I had to get used to with virtual presentations was feeling like I was talking into a black box.”
“So what do you do?”
“I keep my energy high throughout my delivery and animate my voice.
I pretend as though everyone is leaning forward with captivated interest in what I’m saying.
I even dial up the emotion in my delivery in a virtual setting.”
“What about other ways to engage the audience? I can’t just talk for 10 minutes straight.” “Well, there’s a lot you can do, depending on what fits the tone of your talk.
You might share an image rather than a bunch of slides.
You could ask a provocative question and get people to share responses in the chat box.”
“Given that I’m sharing my change story, I could definitely think of some images that come to mind.
Thanks, David. I’m feeling so much better now about the presentation.”
“Hi everyone, thanks for making the time today. I’d like to start off with why now is the right time for MODA to change.”